So, artificial intelligence is going to be the main topic of this course, of course,
but I want to give you a short and very, very high level introduction to AI
to know what you are getting into.
This may be obvious for you, this may be less obvious for some, so don't worry,
I just want to put everyone on the same level as we go along in this course.
So, what is artificial intelligence?
Well, it is the field of computer science dedicated to solving problems
that we commonly associate with human intelligence.
So, what can it be?
For example, it could be image creation where the AI is going to generate an image
that you want based on requirements.
It could be image recognition, so for example, your car is going to have a look
at the stop signs on the street and know when to stop.
It could be speech to text, for example, right now I'm speaking, and I know
that my words are being transcribed into captions by an AI.
There's also for learning, so AI has the ability to adapt to the problems
you have, and therefore giving you a very specialized learning experience.
But for now, right now, you're learning from me, and I promise you, I am a human.
So, how does artificial intelligence work?
Well, we're going to have a look at it in great detail in this course,
but I want to give you a general understanding of it, so we know we're going.
So, usually AI, at this in the modern term and the modern sense of it,
has a training data set.
So, training data sets could be whatever data you want.
In this example, I have a lot of fruits, I have peaches, bananas, and apples.
And someone, usually a data scientist, is going to take this data set and is going to train a model.
Now, training model is basically some code that has some statistical abilities,
and a model is born out of it.
We will look in great details how this works, and for now, let's just understand
that there is a model, and it's basically just smart computer code that is being generated,
thanks to the data.
And so, here is an example of one of these algorithms you can understand,
which is a classification algorithm.
So, the AI model is going to place all the fruits on to access,
or it could be a lot more access, but two for now is easy to understand.
And basically, it's going to group the data together.
And we're going to say in a classification algorithm that the first one is peaches,
and this is where the peaches are on my graph.
Then we have the bananas together, and then we have the apples together.
And how to determine this group, and how to place these elements on this graph
is basically what the data scientist trains the AI model to do.
Now, us as a user, so this is the backend preparation of the model type of stuff,
and us as a user, we're going to be using the model, and how do we use the model?
Well, we show a new image to the model that it hasn't seen before.
So, this image of apple has never been seen before, because look at the train datasets,
the three images of apples that existed before are different.
And so, we give a new image of an apple, but the model has been trained on so many images,
not nine of them, but millions of them, that in the end, it recognizes that,
yes, this is, again, an apple, because it would classify it on the diagram next to all the other apples.
So, AI works like this.
Now, there are tons of different algorithms.
There's tons of different ways to train your model.
To have your data and so on, and we'll do a deep dive on all of this,
but you have, hopefully, now a better understanding of how AI works.
So, let's go back in time, because I think it's important for you to understand where we are with AI today.
So, computer science is very new because, well, before we didn't have computer.
And so, in the 1950s, this was the birth of AI.
So, Alan Turing, who was a mathematician, and when the personality helps really make the whole computer science field exist,
proposes something called the Turing test.
And the Turing test is saying that the machine has intelligence,
if it's able to have a conversation with a human,
and fool the human into making the human think that the human is speaking to another human.
So, if the computer can pretend it's a human, and a human cannot detect this,
then we have achieved artificial intelligence.
And there's another person called John McCarthy,
who is also one of the father of artificial intelligence,
who just invented the term.
So, this is in the 1950s, and all of this is pretty much a dream.
Right now, we don't have, at that time, we don't have anything
that suggests that we will arrive to artificial intelligence,
but they still define test for it, and they describe the term.
Now, in the 1970s, we have what's called expert systems.
And expert systems are like the MyCIN expert system,
which is an AI rule-based system to detect materials.
So, you will see this in greater detail as well,
but you would answer questions.
A lot of them, and then the expert system,
which would be one of the first AI,
would say we think you have this bacteria,
and then we'll propose some kind of treatments.
And in the 1990s, we have the new field of machine learning and data mining.
So, it's not a dream anymore.
Our computers are becoming more and more powerful.
We can collect data, we can organize it,
and we start to have statistical breakthroughs in math
that allows us to design algorithms to start doing machine learning.
In 1997, Deep Blue is here.
And Deep Blue is an AI by IBM,
which has the power to defeat the world champion of chess at a time,
Gary Kasparov.
And it does it by just doing a lot of computations,
analyzing the best moves and playing.
But this is a big one because, well,
before computers would always lose against chess players,
or not always, but against the good ones at least.
But this was the first time that a computer would beat a world champion.
Then, in 2010, we have the Deep Learning Revolution.
So, this is where we are going to have neural networks
and the type of algorithms to data you see in modern AI.
And this is big because now we really have the power
to give true intelligence to our AI models.
And so, in 2016, there's Google,
which creates an algorithm in AI named AlphaGo,
defeating the Go World Champion, Lee Sedol, in 2016.
And this is big because Go is a very advanced game,
more advanced than chess in a way that you cannot compute
all the possible moves like you would in chess.
And so, therefore, the algorithm that IBM employed for Deep Blue
did not work for Google AlphaGo.
So, a new approach was needed.
And this was Google Deep Mine.
And this was really a revolution because
we unlocked a new stage of AI.
And nowadays, we have AI in everyday life.
So, we have virtual systems, autonomous vehicles,
healthcare days, optics, we have chatbots,
we have discussion of ethics and regulations.
And this is why nowadays, we are learning about AI in practical terms.
So, I want to give you a few more use cases for AI.
So, we have good abilities now to transcribe and translate spoken language,
which allows humans to communicate very easily,
even if they don't speak the same language.
We have the games and the games are very, very big fields of research in AI,
because, well, it seems simple, but this is where the breakthroughs happen
and they get applied to everyday life.
So, we have chess, Go, Starcraft, and so on.
AI is not available to help us drive cars or to fly airplanes,
to do speech recognition and generation.
So, we can generate voices that look very human-like nowadays thanks to AI.
Good developers that write code also have now copidots,
which allows them to get suggestions for code,
and this is big because it has improved the productivity of many, many developers.
Doctors are using AI to get assisted in their medical diagnosis.
For example, to find a brain tumor, there's multiple occasions where your AI
does see something that humans don't see.
So, this is very good collaboration.
We have, from a more business perspective,
the automation of many business processes that used to be done manually,
but not can be fully automated thanks to AI agents,
and in the field of fraud detection,
the anti-fraud algorithms are becoming more and more advanced thanks to your AI,
which allows to catch more fraud ahead of time.
So, here is a practical example of how AI can be used.
It's called IDP or Intelligent Document Processing.
So, say for example, we have an invoice, someone takes a picture of an invoice,
and they put the image in the PDF file, and we're supposed to extract the data
out of this invoice to insert it into an invoice processing system.
So, here we have an AI, which is specialized in IDP,
and is going to process an extract data from this document.
For these, there's going to be several sub-AIs that are going to be leveraged.
For example, computer vision to be able to see the image and interpret it.
Deep learning to be able to understand how things work from an image perspective as well.
And natural language processing, NLP, because we need to understand
what everything means in order to extract it correctly.
So, for example, the seller example ink is going to be extracted by the AI.
So, it's the buyer, that's me, it's the fanmeric,
as well as all the items as well as quantity and price.
And this is very important because now all this data
can be automatically inserted into a database where things can be processed much more naturally.
And so, this is complicated to develop, of course,
but it is possible nowadays and has allowed AI to be in our life.
So, nowadays, what is AI?
So, we'll see this diagram a few times in the course.
So, we have AI and AI is the overall field, okay?
But within AI, we have machine learning.
This is when the data is going to be used to train the AI models.
Then we have deep learning, this is when we use something called neural networks
and we have a look at those, of course, in details in this course.
And then we have generative AI or gen AI.
And nowadays, if I tell you, or if I tell anyone in the streets that have an AI,
they already think about gen AI.
So, AI is the greater field.
Gen AI is what people think about when we talk about AI.
So, this is chat GPT when you have a chatbot or Dell E for image generation and so on.
But me, I will try to refer as much as possible as gen AI for the generative AI and AI for the overall field.
Don't worry, we'll have a look at all these things in detail.
But this was a short introduction into AI.
So, I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.